Avtar Singh

617.838.8882 | 508 S. Wall St. #132 Carbondale, IL 62901 | avtars1289@gmail.com

Profile

Enthusiastic go-getter looking to grow my strong software engineering and web development background Relocating to the Bay Area

Military Experience

U.S. Marine Corps Aviation Logistics Squadron 12 Served 4 years of Active Duty in Asia-Pacific Region Honorable Discharge and Good Conduct Medal

Education

Southern Illinois University Carbondale December 2018 Bachelor's in Computer Science, Marketing Minor

Experience

Administrative Assistant

Jan 2018 – Jun 2018

Marion VA Medical Center

- Reviewed 8,000 veteran patient records across Southern Illinois to assess healthcare needs
- Called inactive patients to schedule appointments to accommodate insurance policies
- Collect answers to survey questions regarding pain management and record data
- Research patient policies for memorial services and create easy-to-follow manual for veterans and their family members

Combat Marksmanship Coach

Jun 2013 - Aug 2014

U.S. Marine Corps

- Train individuals in both dry and live fire training in all phases of Marine Corps marksmanship
- Conducted demo fire and one-on-one coaching depending on shooters' needs
- Assisted in arrangement of safety procedures and lectures in individual and group lessons
- Demonstrated proper cleaning and usage of weaponry to students

Aircraft Maintenance Administration Specialist

Jan 2011 – Aug 2014

U.S. Marine Corps

- Managed and screened 13 aircraft log books and more than 50 aeronautical equipment service recrods for any mathematical erros ensuring integrity of the Aircraft and installed component
- Maintained documentation of all daily and hourly inspections of aircraft and components
- Analyzed all component usage while paying close attention to any removal and replacement near due, ensuring safety of each Aircraft
- Submitted aircrafts' mission capabilities reports through analyzing maintenance data to general officers via naval messages giving a clear picture of the unit mission capability in a timely manner
- Managed personnel to ensure maintenance work orders are documented correctly by planning and executing daily work task resulting in accurate record keeping of more than 2000 monthly work orders and the safe flights of 13 combat airplanes

Barracks Manager

Jan 2010 – Jan 2011

U.S. Marine Corps

- Performed billeting operations to include assigning troop housing, issuing and clearing of non-tenant facilities and property accountability
- Maintained and inventoried furniture and equipment worth in excess of \$200,000
- Coordinated daily escorts for maintenance contractors